# DIPAYAN MALLICK

Information Technology Delivery Manager

Email: dipayan.mallick@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Ph: +91 9330892318 | Kolkata, India

#### Career Profile

Delivery Manager with 15 years' experience implementing Information Technology Solutions for Fortune 500 companies in the Financial, Telcom and Manufacturing sectors across India, United State & Benelux. Conceptualized, Transitioned, Retained and Maintained high-performing teams for Infrastructure Services large delivery programs and Global operations of enterprise customers with operating model of 20K- 30K devices and workforce exceeding 100+FTE with revenue of \$50M USD. Optimized Margin for project using levers like Automation and Left Shifting of jobs.

#### **Skills**

Core Competencies include Designing and executing High Maturity Service Delivery, Project Scoping, Transition Management, Auditing and Delivery Excellence for high Engagement Health Score, consulting and providing advisory services for Digital Application, DevOps, Deep Analysis of Incident data, Intelligent Task Automation, Script based Automation using tools like Ayehu, Service Now Orchestration, Risk management, Service Now Reporting for tracking KPIs and SOW obligation, Business Continuity Planning, Conflict Resolution.

# **Professional Experience**

# @ Cognizant (2010-Present)

#### **Offshore Delivery Manager**





2017-Current V Kolkata, Pune, Bangalore, IND

- Perform overall Delivery Management for engagement with major US company in industrial and Agriculture Equipment Sector along with Migration projects for New Age Storage and Applications which has a global roll-out across 450+ sites in 12 Data centres.
- Provide Delivery and manage Operations via a cross-border team of 100+ team members, facilitate transformation programs on Hyperconverged platforms like Simplivity, Nutanix and Containerization of Middleware services.
- Governing the program for Automation of BAU activities like Incidents, Task and Vulnerability to decrease the MTTR and increase the FLR of the overall ticket flow.
- Responsible for Risk Management via RAID tracker for the engagement with structured approached of 3L5Y analysis with a timeline of mitigation in liaison with various stakeholders.
- Define Project approach, Success Criterion in alignment with internal (management) and external (client) needs, Conflict Resolution and maintain the EHS score of the program via weekly, monthly Service review, and yearly Business Review.
- Responsible for having Zero Non-Compliance in SSAE Type 2 external Audit
- Drafting and delivery of yearly Kaizen programs for Digital Transformation and Process Improvements and Re-engineering.
- Manage Employee Development Program via reskilling and upskilling of experience resources in new technology and create left shift movement for Trainee/junior in the team
- Responsible for Facility management for captive setup and
- Review SOW as and when required and arrange amendment of SOW / RFP for new scope of work

#### **Transition Manager**



2017-2018



- Coordinated 3<sup>rd</sup> Party Knowledge Transfer between other Service Provider & and Offshore Team for smooth handover adhering the Project Timeline for Knowledge Transition
- Analysed the SOW GAP and Transition Risk during Knowledge Transition Phase

# **Onsite Technical Manager**





2015 -2017 Amsterdam, Den Haag, NL

- Started as Unix Team lead to support Europe's one of the major Telecom Operator based in Netherlands.
- Promoted to Onsite Manager role for manging the Support to the Infrastructure Service Delivery having Wintel, Unix physical and Virtual servers managed by VMWare VSphere Infrastructure, in a complex environment with SQL and Oracle Databases, Hitachi/NetApp as backend Storage and Citrix XenApp for published applications.
- Led the project for Data Center Consolidation for Benelux based Major Bank in Belgium
- Implementation of Confluence as ITIL tool and provided maturity to the Service Catalogue of Client.
- Implementation of RedHat Satellite and Puppet for Linux Life Cycle Management
- Implemented Security Benchmark validation methodology to meet the Security compliance guideline suggested by External Auditor

#### **Unix Team Lead**



2010-2015





- Joined as Onsite Linux Engineer to support Europe's one of the major Investment Banking Company based in Netherlands.
- Provided End to End Support for RHEL Environment including Patching, Security Remediation, BAU Support
- Developed and deployed Automation of Daily Checks for production environment vi HPSM
- Implemented CSI Benchmark for Security Compliance

#### @ Open Source Software Solutions (2008-2010)

#### **System Engineer**

- Requirement Analysis
- Implementation of LAMP Platform for Drupal 6.0
- Troubleshooting technical issues as and when required along OS process monitoring
- Implementation Apache webserver integrated with Debian 5.0
- Troubleshooting technical issues as and when required.
- Database management and replication implementation,
- Backup management
- Documenting and creating knowledge bases for the entire project

# **Previous Professional Experience**

### 

Worked as System & Network Administrator for maintaining Kolkata and Washington DC
Office Datacentres and Virtual Private Servers hosted on Linode VPS.

# ® Kolkata Metropolitan Development Authority (2006-2007)

- Worked as Data Entry Operator cum System Engineer for Government of West Bengal's Land Acquisition Cell
- Digitization of Land Information for BLRO offices under KMDA

# @ Brainware Academy (2005-2007)

• Started career as Linux Trainer

# Professional Training & Certification

- Six Sigma Yellow Belt Training (Cognizant Internal Certification)
- ITIL V3 (Cognizant Internal Certification)
- CIS Cloud Awareness Cognizant Technology Solutions
- Estimation Techniques Cognizant Technology Solutions
- Google Certified Associate Cloud Engineer (Certificate Credential)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (BLOKE4ELCERQ1L3Z)
- Redhat Certified System Administrator in Openstack (Certificate Credential)
- Redhat Certified System Engineer (Certificate Credential)

#### **Technical Experience**

Linux Administration, Shell Scripting, RedHat Satellite, Puppet, DevOps, GitHub, Docker, Excel, Service Now Reporting, Tableau Reporting, Networking, Routing & Switching, SEO, Server Hardware Support, Storage on NAS & SAN









#### Education

- 1. B.Sc. Physics Hons. (2002) CALCUTTA UNIVERSITY India, WB
- 2. Master of Ecology & Environment (2004) (Distance)
- 3. Diploma in Hardware & Network (West Bengal University of Technical Education)

#### Professional Reference

# Subhendu Shaw, Delivery Director @ Cognizant

Ph: +1 (612) 850-5094

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/subhendushaw/

Virgil Ferrier, Co-owner & Managing Director bij VIRGON BV, Netherland

Ph: +31 0653337748

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/virgil-ferrier-68709612/

# **Achievement**

Spot Award, Q2 2016 given by AVP-CIS, for Contribution to Liberty Global Project in Netherlands.

Certificate for Appreciation given by Sr. Vice President in 2013 for extraordinary effort in ING Project,

Associate of the Quarter - Q4, 2012

Sd/	
Dipayan Mallick	

Place: - Kolkata